Guide to the Department of Sociology, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Sociology, Yale University, records
1913-1967
RU 421
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(10 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and memoranda documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Sociology.
Yale University. Dept. of Sociology
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to Series II is restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and memoranda documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Sociology.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Subject Files. III. Maurice R. Davie Files on Albert G. Keller. IV. Sumner Today. V. Surveys and Case Files.
Sociology -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Davie, Maurice R. (Maurice Rea), 1893-1964; Keller, Albert Galloway, 1874-1956; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Dept. of Sociology
- Records, 1913-1967; Accession 1970-A-001
  - I. Correspondence
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - D - F (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - G (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - H (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - I - L (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - M (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - N - P (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - R - S (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - T - Z (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Yale University official (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - II. Subject Files, 1913-1967
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2043.
    - General A (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - American Economic Review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Anthropology Club (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Semitism (Eastern Sociological Society) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - General B (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General C (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - General D (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Department -- current (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Department enrollment (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Dissertations (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Dissertations (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dissertations (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Education: general (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fellowships and Scholarships -- Graduate (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Fellowships and Scholarships -- Graduate (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - General G (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Graduate applications, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Graduate course of study (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Graduate credits and records (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Graduate record examination language requirement (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Graduate School: general (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - General YT (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Housing, 1926-1946 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - General I, 1923-1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Inquiries for information (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Institute for Propaganda Analysis, 1938-1947 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - General J, 1937-1947 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Jobs, current - requests and recommendations (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Jobs - Appltcations for jobs at Yale (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - General K (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - General L (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - General M (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - M.A. Degree Committee (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Macbundy, George Grant academic worksheets (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Mansfield-Southbury Joint Committee (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Negro Study Organization (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - New Haven Defense Council (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Parnassus on Wheels (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Personnel (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Ph.D. Degree (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Powdermaker, Hortense (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Proposed projects (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Racca - On Fascism (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Records of students, 1913-1930 (Box 6, Folder 62 - 63)
    - Reports, 1939-1942 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Social Ecology of New Haven (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Soctal Science: list of courses at Yale, 1872-1937 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Sociology Club (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Sociology Club (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Sumner Club, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Unemployment Survey (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Work Sheets, 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - WPA (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - III. Maurice R. Davie Files on Albert G. Keller, 1924-1967
    - Correspondence file, 1924-1937 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence file, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence file, 1941-1956, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Academic worksheets, 1926-1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Applied sociology" two typescripts with corrections, 1936 January (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "What of Loyal Opposition?" typescript, 1941 December (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "English Teaching and the Classics" published article, 1945 July 28 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Bibliographies, 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia and obituaries, 1956-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - IV. Sumner Today
    - Sumner Today (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Comments (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Originals of mimeographed materials (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Expenditures (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Essay book and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 6 - 7)
  - V. Surveys and Case Files
    - Incomes and living costs of a university faculty
      - Questionnaires (Box 10, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Sample Family Survey (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Social Case Work
      - Case study questionnaires (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Hospitals (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Board of Health (Box 10)
      - Soclal Case Records (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Social Service Records (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Copy of report: Survey of Social Case Records, New Haven Social Agencies (Box 10, Folder 9 - 10)
  - VI. Financial
    - Requisition invoices, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Requisition invoices, 1942-1944 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Requisition invoices, 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Requisition invoices, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Requisition invoices, 1938-1948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Deptartment requisitions, 1948-1957 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Requisitions, receipts, etc., 1946-1952 (Box 12, Folder 8-12, Box 11, Folder 7)